

PERSON

child

Name Mike Guwak
Address Sachsenring 13a,
65817 Eppstein - Germany
Phone+ 49 1573 | 764 92 89
E-Mail info@mikeguwak.de
Website mikeguwak.de
Born on 4 April 1971 in Marburg,
Germany
Nationality German

CORE COMPETENCES

Marital Status Divorced, one

- Management & structuring of IT operating units
- Introduction & optimisation of IT service processes (ITIL-based)
- Strategic further development of IT infrastructures
- Creation & maintenance of emergency plans, operational documentation
- Coordination of service providers & external partners
- SLA-/KPI-supported service monitoring
- Interface management between IT & specialist departments
- Analysing & improving internal IT processes
- Design & implementation of technical solutions
- Communication security at all levels
- Public tenders (evaluation & technology)

MIKE GUWAK

"Being an experienced IT professional with more than 25 years of practical experience in infrastructure management, system administration and IT service responsibility, I stand for stability, efficiency and high quality standards in IT operations. I combine strong analytical skills with practical implementation expertise - both in corporate structures and in medium-sized companies. My profile is characterised by independent action, a holistic understanding of IT and a technical flair for dealing with complex infrastructures."

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fibrolux GmbH | Hofheim, Germany Senior IT-Systemadministrator Since July 2023

- Responsible for setting up, operating and further developing the entire IT infrastructure
- Introduction of proactive monitoring with Zabbix to monitor business-critical systems
- Maintenance and further development of IT documentation and emergency plans
- Administration of the Microsoft 365 environment with a focus on SharePoint, Teams, Microsoft Defender, Intune and Exchange Online
- Interface function between management, specialist departments and external IT service providers

SOLVVision AG | Frankfurt, Germany Consultant Infrastructure January 2023 - June 2023

- Supporting customers in the analysis and optimisation of their IT infrastructure
- Processing complex tickets in the area of infrastructure via ServiceNow
- Structuring and evaluation of CMDBs to improve data quality
- Conception and development of virtual data centres for enterprise solutions

Red Reply GmbH | Frankfurt, Germany
IT Service Manager January 2021 - December 2022

- Monthly creation of SLA reports and service desk evaluations
- Support and maintenance of the Oracle ZFS storage systems
- Responsibility for 2nd level support in the context of business-critical applications
- Introduction of standardised support processes based on ITIL

NECDIS GmbH | Frankfurt, Germany Senior IT Systems Engineer July 2019 - December 2020

- Operation and maintenance of the internal IT system landscape incl. CRM/ERP
- Creation of technical solution concepts for customer projects
- Technical evaluation of public tenders
- Preparation of offers, communication with customers and suppliers
- Coordination with manufacturers and external partners

CERTIFICATIONS

- Microsoft Defender Fending Off Threats
- Microsoft Teams, Intune, Sharepoint Online
- Zabbix Monitoring -Introduction & Operation
- Nginx High Performance Web
 Server
- Fail2Ban Protection
 Against Brute Force Attacks
- Veeam Backup & Replication -Compact Course
- Microsoft Azure Basics & Administration
- Windows Server 2022 -Administration

IT SKILLS

- Operating Systems: Windows Server, Linux (Debian, Ubuntu)
- Cloud & Microsoft: Microsoft 365, Azure, Intune, SharePoint, Teams
- Backup & Recovery: Veeam, Oracle ZFS Storage
- Monitoring & Logging: Zabbix, Nginx, Fail2Ban
- Network & Security: Firewall configuration, access controls
- Service & Ticketing: Jira, Jira SM, Confluence, ServiceNow
- Scripting & Automation:
 PowerShell (basics), Bash
- Virtualisation & Infrastructure: setting up virtual data centres

REFERENCES

Available on request

bluetelligence GmbH | Wiesbaden, Germany
Quality Manager Enterprise Glossary February 2019 June 2019

- Responsibility for testing the software "Enterprise Glossary"
- Creation of extensive product documentation in a wiki (Atlassian Confluence)
- Support in first level support

ORACLE Deutschland B.V. & Co KG | Dreieich, Germany Senior Technical Support Engineer July 2010 - January 2019

- Support of the following Oracle products: SL8500, SL4000, SL3000, SL150, L500, L700, SL24/48, StorageTek SAM-FS/QFS software, Solaris
- Fault diagnosis with Remote Support WebEx or SDP2
- Provision of problem isolation and resolution for very complex problems
- Support for possible future problem determination/solution

Sun Microsystems GmbH | Langen, Germany
TSC Engineer CT3 October 2000 - June 2010

GE CompuNet | Frankfurt, Germany System Engineer Support Services October 1996 -September 2000

Systematics Rhein-Main | Wiesbaden, Germany System Technician November 1995 - September 1996

Henning Sicherheit GmbH | Hainburg, Germany Energy Electronics Technician November 1994 -February 1995

Siemens AG | Frankfurt, Germany
Energy Electronics Technician - Systems
Engineering

June 1992 - October 1994

EDUCATION

Siemens AG | Frankfurt, Germany Apprenticeship - Energy Electronics Technician Specialising in Systems Engineering September 1988 - June 1992

Konrad-Haenisch-Schule | Frankfurt, Germany
High School Certificate
1982 - 1988